# **Bret Petersen**

# Full Stack Web Developer

Minneapolis, MN 55404 (willing to relocate) • 415.939.1779 • <u>bretpetersen@gmail.com</u> <u>bretpetersen.com</u> • <u>linkedin.com/in/bret-petersen/</u> • <u>github.com/bretpeters3n</u>

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer with extensive experience in visual design who enjoys the fast-paced environment of the tech industry and being part of pioneering teams. I'm a React-fluent developer who enjoys creating interaction and animation filled mobile and desktop experiences.

Core Competencies and Skills: Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for React.js.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

React.js, HTML, Javascript, CSS, jQuery, Responsive Design, Express, SQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Express, Unit Testing, Node.js, ORM, MVC, Snapshot Testing, ES6, and Git.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **True Crime Quiz**

Served as project lead while developing an application allowing users to test their true crime knowledge. *Tools used:* React.js, Framer Motion, Auth0, Bootstrap, Javascript, Mongo Atlas and Heroku.

https://aithub.com/bretpeters3n/true-crime-quiz • https://true-crime-quiz.herokuapp.com

#### **Cat Memory**

Acted as project lead in developing an application allowing users to play a game of memory with cat photos. *Tools used:* Javascript, Bootstrap, the Cat API, and GitHub Pages.

https://github.com/bretpeters3n/cat-memory • https://bretpeters3n.github.io/cat-memory

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**UX/UI Designer** • Irish Titan, St. Louis Park, MN

03/2020 - 06/2021

- Communicated with clients to discover their needs and fine tune their projects.
- Researched and tested e-commerce apps for use on our client's online stores.

Key achievement: Expedited adoption of Figma as our main software design tool.

#### Web Specialist • United Healthcare, Hopkins, MN

08/2019 - 12/2019

- Animated advertisements and designed emails.
- Helped usher in more efficient email coding with the use of templates.

Key achievement: Received 'Employee of the Month' honor.

# Web Animator • Target, Minneapolis, MN

07/2018 - 02/2019

- Created animated advertisements while working alongside a team of designers and developers.
- Introduced 3D animation into advertisements to increase their noticeability.

Key achievement: Facilitated faster workflow using Hype as main animation software.

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Certificate • University of Minnesota

Fall 2021

UX Certificate • Brainco (Minneapolis, MN)

BFA in Graphic Design • University of Minnesota Duluth